{"message":"Deploy instructions ready.","tool_purpose":"Return deployment instructions the model MUST follow.","process_rules":["Decide early whether this is a new app or an update to an existing app.","NEW APPS: Call get_app_template with chosen app_type and frontend_template, then call get_appdeploy_sdk_reference for the exact AppDeploy features the app will use before writing feature code.","UPDATES: Use get_apps to discover app_id, then inspect the current snapshot with src_glob/src_grep/src_read as needed before editing."],"goal":"Goal: one deploy_app call. If validation fails, fix all returned errors in one pass and retry (avoid iterative one-error retries).","sdk_architecture_rules":["Prefer frontend-only by default. Use frontend+backend only when the app truly needs backend capabilities.","For exact backend shape, feature rules, and SDK methods, use get_app_template plus get_appdeploy_sdk_reference with the features the app will use."],"calling_backend":["Frontend must call the AppDeploy backend only with api from @appdeploy/client; do not use fetch() or axios() for AppDeploy backend routes.","Include the api feature in get_appdeploy_sdk_reference when you need exact transport examples, route patterns, or client call shapes."],"partial_updates":["UPDATES: Use diffs[] for surgical changes and content for full replacements.","Never resend unchanged files; deploy_app merges only the changes you send."],"template_based_deployment":["NEW APPS: 'frontend_template' MUST be provided; backend auto-includes all template files as the base.","Only send: ","  (1) files that don't exist in the template (e.g., src/components/MyWidget.tsx), ","  (2) diffs to modify template files (e.g., add dependencies to package.json, customize src/App.tsx).","Do NOT send template files verbatim - they are auto-included."],"file_diffs":["diffs[] apply to the template base for new apps and the current snapshot for updates.","Use content for entirely new files or full replacements; use diffs[] when you can anchor on exact existing text.","Each diff is { from, to, multiple? } and fails if 'from' is not found."],"remote_filesystem":["AppDeploy maintains a remote source snapshot for each app - this is what actually runs in production.","Every deploy_app updates this snapshot: merge with template base (new app), or merge with existing snapshot (update).","The remote snapshot is the source of truth, essentially like a git repo. Your local files or context may drift after multiple edits.","If uncertain about current state, query it: src_glob (list files), src_grep (search), src_read (read content). All require app_id.","Use get_app_versions to list versions; apply_app_version to roll back."],"required_files":{"new_apps":["files[] MUST contain ONLY: (1) new files not in template (use content), (2) diffs to modify template files.","Do NOT include unmodified template files - they are auto-included."],"updates":["files[] MUST contain ONLY changed files. Use diffs[] for incremental changes; use content for anything else."]},"implementation_checklist":["1. NEW APPS: Write 3-10 tests in tests/tests.txt and mark exactly one [sanity] test.","1b. UPDATES: Review tests/tests.txt and update it with diffs[] if user-visible behavior is changing.","2. NEW APPS: call get_app_template; UPDATES: inspect the current snapshot with get_apps/src_* before editing.","3. Call get_appdeploy_sdk_reference with the exact features the app will use before implementing backend SDK logic.","4. Review the returned get_app_template/get_appdeploy_sdk_reference results and decide the changed files, tests, and imports before writing or editing files.","5. Write all app files to a local working directory on disk. NEW APPS: create the directory from template output. UPDATES: sync the remote snapshot locally first, then apply edits.","6. Build the frontend and backend changes needed for the requested behavior.","7. Call update_coding_progress on significant milestones during implementation and validation using 'step' for the milestone label and 'current_task' or 'note' for the short description.","8. Prepare the deploy: use upload_assets to send the local tree (default). Only call deploy_app without upload_id for trivially small inline changes. If a required file is missing, add it to the checklist first."],"hard_rules":["NEW APPS: MUST call get_app_template with app_type and frontend_template before writing code.","UPDATES: MUST inspect the current snapshot with get_apps/src_glob/src_grep/src_read as needed before preparing deploy_app changes.","Do not start writing or editing files until the required get_app_template/get_appdeploy_sdk_reference calls have returned and you have reviewed them to decide the implementation plan.","Always include app_id, app_name, and app_type. Never send the string 'undefined' as app_id.","deletePaths is update-only and must not overlap files[].","package.json must include scripts.build and required dependencies, but never add @appdeploy/client or @appdeploy/sdk.","Frontend must never import @appdeploy/sdk. Backend must never import @appdeploy/client.","SPAs must not use absolute client routes; use HashRouter.","frontend+backend apps must extend backend/index.ts and frontend must call backend routes only through api.<method>(...) from @appdeploy/client.","When creating new files with exports, add the matching imports in files that use them."],"preflight_checklist":["Confirm the app is classified correctly as NEW APP or UPDATE and the matching workflow was followed.","Confirm app files exist in a local working directory and all file content for deployment is derived from that local tree.","Confirm get_appdeploy_sdk_reference was called for every backend feature the app uses.","Confirm the required get_app_template/get_appdeploy_sdk_reference results were reviewed and the implementation plan was decided before writing or editing files.","Confirm update_coding_progress was called for significant milestones before deploy_app using 'step' for the milestone label and 'current_task' or 'note' for the short description.","Confirm tests/tests.txt exists, has 3-10 stateless tests with exactly one [sanity], and matches current user-visible behavior.","Confirm app_id/app_type/frontend_template/description fields match the create-vs-update path.","Confirm files[] contains only changed files and every entry uses either content or diffs, not both.","Confirm deletePaths, if present, is update-only and does not overlap files[].","Confirm frontend never imports @appdeploy/sdk and backend never imports @appdeploy/client.","Confirm frontend calls the AppDeploy backend only with api from @appdeploy/client.","Confirm package.json uses bare module imports for AppDeploy packages and does not list them as dependencies.","If SPA routing is used, confirm there are no absolute client routes and HashRouter is used.","If existing code violates these rules, fix it before calling deploy_app."],"package_json_rules":["Include 'scripts.build' and required 'dependencies'.","Output raw JSON only (no markdown/code fences).","Content must be a JSON object."],"custom_api_usage":["For custom backend routes, define them in backend/index.ts and follow the api feature rules/examples from get_appdeploy_sdk_reference instead of inventing your own transport contract."],"backend_persistence":["For backend capabilities and exact SDK methods, use get_appdeploy_sdk_reference with the exact features the app will use and do not invent SDK methods."],"cron_jobs":["Use cron.json only when the app actually needs scheduled work.","Include the cron feature in get_app_template/get_appdeploy_sdk_reference for exact format and examples."],"auth_usage":["Frontend auth comes from @appdeploy/client; backend auth and middleware come from @appdeploy/sdk.","Include the auth feature in get_appdeploy_sdk_reference for exact scopes, middleware, and protected-route rules."],"notifications_usage":["Frontend notifications use @appdeploy/client and backend delivery uses @appdeploy/sdk; never call Firebase/FCM APIs directly.","Include the notifications feature in get_appdeploy_sdk_reference for exact subscription and delivery examples."],"ui_guidance":["Follow the user's requested product behavior closely and ship a polished, responsive UI that hides technical internals from end users.","Use get_app_template as the structural baseline and preserve template quality while customizing the experience.","Use any UI skill you have freely; do not limit your design or code to AppDeploy-provided UI, CSS, or icon templates."],"mobile_game_guidance":["Only when the user asks for a mobile-first game: keep gameplay within the viewport and design controls for touch-first input."],"status_behavior":["deploy_app is non-blocking; deployments typically complete within a few seconds.","'deploying' is a success in-progress state, not an error. Do not redeploy to unstick.","After deploy_app returns, always call get_app_status until status is 'ready', 'failed', or 'deleted'.","Always read response.message and validation feedback on every status check.","If get_app_status includes deployment.url while status is 'deploying', surface that exact URL to the user immediately.","If still deploying or deleting, wait at least 5 seconds before checking again.","Backend console.error() and console.warn() calls are automatically captured and surfaced in get_app_status backend error logs. Use them for debugging."],"post_deploy_workflow":{"poll":{"tool":"get_app_status","interval_seconds":5,"until_status":["ready","failed","deleted"]},"always_review":["Always read response.message and validation errors/warnings.","If get_app_status returns an error summary, treat it as authoritative.","If deployment.url is present at any status (including 'deploying'), immediately show `Live URL: <url>` to the user before continuing to poll."],"on_ready":["If validation errors/warnings exist, show them to the user and fix automatically.","Return the public URL to the user."],"on_failed":["Show the failure summary to the user.","Review the errors field and files_to_fix in the response.","Prioritize fixing files listed in files_to_fix; for unlisted errors, fix the relevant file.","Prefer diffs[] for surgical fixes (works for both new template-based apps and updates). Use content for new files not in template.","Fix issues automatically and redeploy."],"on_deleted":["Confirm deletion to the user."]},"routing":{"spa":{"forbid_absolute_routes":true,"allowed_strategies":["relative routes","HashRouter"]}},"imports":{"forbid_frontend":["@appdeploy/sdk"],"forbid_backend":["@appdeploy/client"]},"backend_entrypoint_path":"backend/index.ts","frontend_backend_calling_rule":"Frontend must call the AppDeploy backend only using api.<method>(...) from @appdeploy/client (no fetch('/api/...') or axios('/api/...') to the AppDeploy backend).","local_workflow":["Always write app files to a local working directory on disk. This is your working copy and the source of truth for all deploy operations.","The remote snapshot is the canonical deployed state (like a git remote). For UPDATES, sync before editing: use src_glob/src_read to pull the latest snapshot into your local working directory, then edit locally.","For NEW APPS, create the local working directory from get_app_template output, then develop locally.","Use upload_assets to send files to the server â this is the default for all deploys. Only call deploy_app without upload_id for trivially small inline changes (e.g. a one-line fix, a small diff).","If local filesystem access is truly unavailable, fall back to in-memory edits and send only the minimal changed files.","Keep local-only metadata (app_id, notes) outside the deploy tree."]}
